<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Core dump</title>
    <link>http://mgdelacroix.es/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Core dump</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://mgdelacroix.es/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying a python script</title>
      <link>http://mgdelacroix.es/post/deploying-a-python-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mgdelacroix.es/post/deploying-a-python-script/</guid>
      <description>Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing a lot of python to script some common processes in a large infrastructure. Those scripts require some python libraries which are not part of the standard library nor installed by default in all systems. For example, I love how docopt manages the arguments of a python script, or using the YAML format for my config files instead of INI.
During the development stage, I usually manage those dependencies using pip and virtualenv, but I would like my deployment to require only python3 installed in the remote machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance SQLite output</title>
      <link>http://mgdelacroix.es/post/enhance-sqlite-output/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mgdelacroix.es/post/enhance-sqlite-output/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing some development in Baoqu with SQLite recently, and one of the problems I&amp;rsquo;ve faced is that the default output from a query in the SQLite client is too basic, almost confusing:
sqlite&amp;gt; select * from users; 1|Ramira 2|Maria 3|Yamilo 4|Mario 5|Pérez-Reverte 6|Yisus 7|Miguel 8|Marta 9|andy 10|lol 11|lol2 12|lolaso  That&amp;rsquo;s a simple query, let&amp;rsquo;s complicate it a little more:
sqlite&amp;gt; select * from users as u inner join users_circles as uc on u.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encrypt a USB drive with LUKS</title>
      <link>http://mgdelacroix.es/post/encrypt-a-usb-drive-with-luks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mgdelacroix.es/post/encrypt-a-usb-drive-with-luks/</guid>
      <description>One of the best options we have to encrypt a USB is to use the Linux Unified Key Setup or LUKS. Through this process, we will format and generate a completely encrypted partition that will require a password to be accesed.
Requirements The only requirement is the cryptsetup program, that can be installed through your favourite distribution&amp;rsquo;s package manager. In the case of Debian/Ubuntu, you just need to run</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gogs is now available in spanish!</title>
      <link>http://mgdelacroix.es/post/gogs-is-now-available-in-spanish/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mgdelacroix.es/post/gogs-is-now-available-in-spanish/</guid>
      <description>This has been the second year I went to FOSDEM. Is a great conference to learn, get together with friends that are spread across the world and enjoy Open Source.
Being there and seeing the awesome things people were doing made me think about my last contributions to the community and how shy they are. A lot of times I&amp;rsquo;ve rejected contributing to a project or publishing a project or a library I&amp;rsquo;m working on due its early stage or the idea of the code or the approach &amp;ldquo;not being good enough&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geb 101: Simple Scripts</title>
      <link>http://mgdelacroix.es/post/geb-101-simple-scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mgdelacroix.es/post/geb-101-simple-scripts/</guid>
      <description>These days I’m in between projects, so I decided to automate a task related to a web interface and a tedious list shaped as an HTML form. This automation would imply two processes: parsing an HTML page and filling some fields in another page, plus some small and simple processing.
I had two options, to use HTTP directly through HTTP Builder or something like that or to code various small scripts with Geb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About to start</title>
      <link>http://mgdelacroix.es/post/about-to-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mgdelacroix.es/post/about-to-start/</guid>
      <description>Expect new content here soon&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>